<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<ModMetaData>
    <name>VFE Factories: Buffs and tweaks</name>
    <author>Kimoju</author>
    <packageId>Kimo.VFEF.rebalance</packageId>
    <supportedVersions>
		<li>1.6</li>
    </supportedVersions>
	<modDependencies>
		<li>
			<packageId>VanillaExpanded.VFEFactory</packageId>
			<displayName>Vanilla Furniture Expanded - Factory</displayName>
			<steamWorkshopUrl>https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3686924415</steamWorkshopUrl>
		</li>
	</modDependencies>
	<loadAfter>
		<li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Odyssey</li>
		<li>dubwise.dubsbadhygiene</li>
		<li>rebuild.cotr.doorsandcorners</li>
		<li>VanillaExpanded.VFEFactory</li>
	</loadAfter>
    <description>	 [h1] What does this mod do? [/h1] 

I procrastinated way too hard doing this, it should have been out a lot sooner, but oh well.
This mods add and tweaks a number of bills/interaction in VFE Factory with two goals in mind:

-First and most importantly, balance. Currently, factories are more expensive, a lot slower, they drain your power grid and most of all, require a HUGE footprint. 
Now, it's no secret than any recruited raider can keep up while being a lot easier to get, maintain, and even the uptime issue can be fixed very easily and cheaply with drugs, or even stuff like sleep supressor, frenzy inducer, and even genes and bionics if you don't minde a slightly bigger investment.
Long story short, large footprint is a cripling weakness, and permanant uptime is not that big of a deal. 

Sadly, most of the important stuff is locked behind c# stuff, but I buffed what was the most obvious and accessible in xml.
With that being said, I did not have as much time as I wished to play with factories, so I probably missed things, feel free to let me know.

-Second, simply add more recipes and support some others mods I play with. 
Again, If I missed something that would make sense to turn into a factory bill, let me know. I'll most likely stick to integrations within VE mods and other mods I personally use though. 

[h1]For now, this is what is being changed:[/h1] 

- All drill bills are 20% faster.
Hopes this helps make factory drills more in line with an unaugmented pawn operating a deep drill.

- Ores can now be drilled in space.
This change is mainly made to make asteroids bases more interesting

- Added a vacstone bill for drills in orbit
This addition was inspired by [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3695050918] DeRuitertjes's vacstone drill patch.[/url] If you want a standalone version of this patch, I recommande using his!

- All Auto Fish farm bills are twice as fast.
This is still nowhere near enough to make the fish farm worth using, but that was the only thing that could be changed in xml. 

- Added an alternative recipe for Neutroamine using insect meat specifically, with slightly more efficiency. This one isn't really here for balance reasons, just because it's cool and thematically fitting.

- Neutroamine synthetiser require the biofuel refinery research.
This won't impact 99% of colonies, this is just a coherency change

- Removed the "We butchered humans" thought on the human butchering bill.
This one is really self explanatory. If pawns don't care about feeding corpses to pigs, there is no reasons whatsoever to be upset about recycling them in other ways.

- Factory floor no longer slow down pawns, and cost 2 steel instead of 5.
I left the floor required for factory, as it doesn't feel like a big deal since it's now reasonably priced, but I may change my opinion on this.

-Added processes for making glass and balistic glass from Rebuild. They can be made in the auto smelter and the alloy foundry respectively.

-Added process to turn fecal sludge from DBH into chemfuel, at a reduced efficiency. 75 Fecal sludge yield 10 chemfuel (instead of 35) 
Yes, a rare nerf, but the rate at which you can get chemfuel by just shitting is ridiculous. This doesn't impact the manual process on the biofuel refinery, as there already mods out there to patch that

[h1] F.A.Q [/h1] 

Q: Is that it?
A: For now, yes. I wanted to do a LOT more, like allowing the autofarmer to handle plants up to a higher skill, make Fish farm no longer require fish in the water, toning down the energy consumption on overclock and much more, but all this is hardcoded.
If you know your way around c# and would like to contribute to changes like this, hit me up! Likewise, if you find some factories or bill underwhelming, let me know. I only patched the very visible stuff for now.

Q: But that's broken!
A: Beleive it or not, a house sized factory should be able to produce more shit than the first recruited raider you can get your hands on.
Also, drugs, genes, bionics, mechs and other buffs already exist in the game.
Also also, i'll let you in on a little secret. You are responsible of the buttons you press! Shocking, I know.

Q: CE compatible?
A: ¯\_(ツ)_/¯

Q: Is it compatible with [i] insert x mod [/i] in particular ?  
A: Mods that adds bills should work fine with this one. If they patch existing bills, they may or may not conflict. 

Q: Can I add it mid playthrough?
A: You should, but don't try to remove it mid-playthrough

Q: Can I suggest something?
A: Sure, no harm in asking. But unless I think it's a good idea or and it's simple enough for me to do, I probably won't do it.

[h1] Credits [/h1] 

Oskar Potocki and the VE team for VFE factories as well as all the other cool stuff they do.
Sarg for giving tips on how to patch process bills.
DeRuitertjes for the idea of the vacstone bill.

[url=https://ko-fi.com/kimoju] [img]https://i.imgur.com/QGcents.png[/img] [/url] 
All donations goes toward comissioning more complex mods to talented modders </description>
</ModMetaData>